<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://lukemccrone.com">
  <title>Luke McCrone</title>
  <subtitle>Luke McCrone - Legend, legend, and legend.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://lukemccrone.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://lukemccrone.com"/>
  <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://lukemccrone.com</id>
  <author>
    <name>Luke McCrone</name>
    <email>luke.mccrone@imperial.ac.uk</email>
  </author>
    <entry>
      <title>Web Automation With n8n, Telegram, Online Forms, and a Bit of Python</title>
      <link href="https://lukemccrone.com/blog/web-automation/"/>
      <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://lukemccrone.com/blog/web-automation/</id>
      <summary>How I used a bunch of open-source tools to automate the management of my side project.</summary>
      <content type="html">
        <img alt="Web Automation With n8n, Telegram, Online Forms, and a Bit of Python" src="https://lukemccrone.com/posts/2024/web-automation/cover.jpg"/>
        &lt;p&gt;I have a small side project where I sell subscriptions for two &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradingview.com/&quot;&gt;TradingView&lt;/a&gt; scripts. It brings me around $200 each month, and I described its stncelled subscriptions, which takes 1-2 hours per month at maximum. But automating everything required patching together some Python web crawlers, Telegram API, and email clients as well as setting up n8n to orchestrate everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the common tasks that I had to automate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most critical part was automating the process of giving customers access to the scripts when they buy subscriptions through Gumroad. The world doesn&#39;t stop when I go to sleep, and sometimes people buy a subscription in the middle of my night. Most customers are patient and will wait for a few hours (as it&#39;s explained in the product&#39;s description). But every now and then, I have that one type of customer who will start spamming me with emails like &amp;quot;I still don&#39;t have access&amp;quot; after five minutes. I didn&#39;t want to drop whatever I was doing and rush to my computer to give someone access whenever I got an email about a new sale, so I had to automate this process. Gumroad offers a developer-friendly feature called &amp;quot;Ping&amp;quot;, which sends a JSON request to a specific URL each time you make a sale. Unfortunately, TradingView has no official API to manage user access, and when I started this project in 2021, there weren&#39;t even any unofficial ones like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/trendoscope-algorithms/Tradingview-Access-Management&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;. So, I needed a way to automate granting access to the users and sending them an email with confirmation and some useful instructions on how to use the script when they subscribed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were even more access-related actions I wanted to simplify. When someone cancelled their subscription, I had to revoke their access from the day their subscription would expire (which could be immediate if the subscription was cancelled because of a failed payment or up to a year from now if they had a yearly subscription). When people asked for a free trial, I had to give them access for a week. All that would require me to log in to TradingView, navigate to the corresponding script and click through some selection fields to grant access to a given user. I could write a CLI script, but that would require me to use my computer, and sometimes, all I had with me was my phone. So, I&#39;ve decided to write a Telegram bot that I could use to give or remove access since I had Telegram installed both on my phone and on my computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a long time, I was offering a free one-week trial for anyone leaving a comment under one of the paid scripts, meaning I had to check who left a comment and grant them access. This could also be automated - I could ask people to fill in an online form that would send a request to my CLI and automatically grant them seven-day access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;high-level-overview&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;High-level overview &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/web-automation/#high-level-overview&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a diagram of my setup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-250.webp 250w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-600.webp 600w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-920.webp 920w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-2895.webp 2895w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 639px) calc(100vw - 32px), (max-width: 767px) 608px, (max-width: 960px) calc(100vw - 40px), 920px&quot; /&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-250.jpeg 250w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-600.jpeg 600w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-920.jpeg 920w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-2895.jpeg 2895w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 639px) calc(100vw - 32px), (max-width: 767px) 608px, (max-width: 960px) calc(100vw - 40px), 920px&quot; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Diagram of all the n8n workflows&quot; class=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/img/fFeq0QCyl5-250.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;2895&quot; height=&quot;1754&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s break it down by explaining how I got from doing all the work manually to a semi-automated setup where new customers and people requesting a trial get access automatically, and any other permissions management can be done with a Telegram bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;python-script&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Python script &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/web-automation/#python-script&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step was to automate the interactions with TradingView. There is no official API, so I needed a tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://pptr.dev/&quot;&gt;Puppeteer&lt;/a&gt;, which can control a headless browser to automate clicking, typing, and any other website interaction needed to grant or revoke access to my TradingView scripts. I chose the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pyppeteer/pyppeteer&quot;&gt;pyppeteer&lt;/a&gt; package - an unofficial Python port of Puppeteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is the code I wrote to interact with the TradingView website and perform a couple of basic interactions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checking if a given TradingView user has access to a specific script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revoking existing access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding access for a new user. This access could have one of the following expiration dates:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No expiration date - if the function was called without any additional parameter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expire in seven days - if a parameter &amp;quot;t&amp;quot; (that stands for &amp;quot;trial&amp;quot;) was given.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expire on a specific day - in case a numeric value was provided as the last parameter. For example, if I passed the value &amp;quot;20240615&amp;quot;, the access would expire on 2024.06.15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>You Don&#39;t Need Stream Deck, You Need Macros</title>
      <link href="https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/"/>
      <updated>2024-05-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/</id>
      <summary>How can creating your own keyboard shortcuts make your life easier, and why don&#39;t you need a device like Stream Deck for that?</summary>
      <content type="html">
        <img alt="You Don&#39;t Need Stream Deck, You Need Macros" src="https://lukemccrone.com/posts/2024/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/cover.jpg"/>
        &lt;p&gt;One day, during one of those meetings that did not require my full attention, I was doing some work in the background. I muted my microphone, and I was coding away&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Suddenly, someone asked me a question. &amp;quot;Now, where is that goddamn Teams window so I can unmute my microphone?!&amp;quot; - I asked myself, frantically going through my MacOS desktops. I use multiple desktops (or workspaces, as some other operating systems call them), each with one to three apps opened. So, instead of shuffling 20 apps opened on one desktop, I shuffle ten desktops scattered across three monitors. It took a few seconds of awkward silence before I found that Teams window. And it wasn&#39;t even the first time this happened to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;There has to be a better way!&amp;quot; - I thought, again, not for the first time. I&#39;ve decided it&#39;s time to figure out how to set up a &amp;quot;global mute/unmute&amp;quot; button that would work regardless of whether Teams (or any other videoconferencing app) has the focus. One way to solve this problem was to use Elgato&#39;s Stream Deck. I&#39;ve been eyeing it for some time, as many developers claim it&#39;s a very useful device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-stream-deck-really-indispensable-for-a-software-developer&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;Is Stream Deck really indispensable for a software developer? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/#is-stream-deck-really-indispensable-for-a-software-developer&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Stream deck is a fantastic tool, and every developer should have one (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/streamdeckprofiles/comments/y1xger/comment/itkcz9j/?context=3&quot;&gt;or three&lt;/a&gt;)!&amp;quot; is something I&#39;ve heard &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/kurtissfrost/power-at-your-fingertips-3c7k&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dL9-MnQl1Wg&quot;&gt;there&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve put it on a shopping list for Black Friday, hoping I can get a good deal. But as Black Friday was getting close, I asked myself - &lt;em&gt;do I &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; need Stream Deck&lt;/em&gt;? My main driver was to have a global mute/unmute button for those Teams calls when I&#39;m doing something else and suddenly need to unmute myself. Pressing a button to unmute my microphone, say what I need to say, and mute it again without shuffling through multiple windows and desktops would be bliss. But that doesn&#39;t justify shelling out over $100 (or less, for the &amp;quot;mini&amp;quot; version) and putting another device on my already cluttered desk. So, I&#39;ve started reading about other things people do with Stream Deck, especially if they are not streamers but developers like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some good reasons to buy Stream Deck. For example, if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://adam.ac/blog/stream-deck-for-developers/&quot;&gt;SSH to many servers, talk with many people on Slack, generate different Stripe test cases, switch between many Spotify playlists, work on different VS Code projects, and push code to different GitHub repositories&lt;/a&gt; - and all that on a daily basis, then you will probably benefit from using a device that can reduce all those tasks to a press of a button or two. It sounds more useful for people who prefer to click things and press buttons instead of typing all the commands in the terminal. It also works well for those who spend most of their time in one piece of software like AutoCAD or Photoshop, where creating and assigning macros to hardware buttons will save them time. Not to mention that in this line of work, you&#39;re already using a drawing tablet, so you&#39;re used to using different devices apart from a keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some &lt;em&gt;weird but ok&lt;/em&gt; reasons to buy it. Some people use it for home automation - ok, but I&#39;m not going to run to my office to toggle lights in the bedroom. Some use it to start applications - fine, but for me, firing up a launcher like Spotlight/Alfred, typing 2-3 first letters of the app I want to start and pressing enter seems equally fast as pressing a button on an external device&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a typical software developer spends most of their day pressing keys on a keyboard. Everything that Stream Deck does can also be achieved by pressing one or more keys. Some actions will trigger a keyboard shortcut, while others are equivalent to typing commands in the terminal or running a script. &lt;strong&gt;Stream Deck is a glorified macro recorder&lt;/strong&gt;. It comes with a nice app that makes it easier to record those macros. It has colorful icons that catch your eye and pressing a physical button is easier than remembering a shortcut for a specific macro. But most of its functionality can be achieved by recording macros on your computer. If you have a manageable number of macros (or a very good memory of all the shortcuts you defined), it might actually be easier to use your keyboard to trigger the macros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stream Deck is not a big device (especially if you go for the mini version that has six buttons), but it&#39;s another device you would need to carry with you if you go somewhere. A keyboard, on the other hand, is usually an integrated part of your laptop. Where your laptop goes, your keyboard goes too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;callout-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ve. A device like Stream Deck (or one of its cheaper or more customizable alternatives) is just more convenient for me. Pressing a colorful button with a label takes no mental effort. On the other hand, trying to remember how to trigger some less often-used shortcuts can be a bit more demanding, especially if I&#39;m in the middle of thinking about something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to keep the Stream Deck because I found several additional uses for it (that I will describe in another article). If I were to use it only to mute/unmute my microphone, I would definitely stick with the macro on my keyboard instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-find-unused-key-combinations&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;How do I find unused key combinations? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/#how-do-i-find-unused-key-combinations&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about Stream Deck or a similar device is that all of their buttons come with different key codes. There is no risk that pressing a button on a device like Stream Deck will trigger a different action, for example, from the currently opened application. But if you want to start assigning custom shortcuts on your keyboard, this might be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When defining keyboard shortcuts that will trigger your macros, you need to find a combination of keys not used by any application. Otherwise, if you try to use a shortcut, the current application will intercept it and perform a completely different action. Assigning custom actions to shortcuts like &amp;quot;cmd+s&amp;quot; (&amp;quot;ctrl+s&amp;quot; for Linux/Windows users) or &amp;quot;cmd+w&amp;quot; is off the table because, in most programs, they are already used to save the file or close the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are some combinations of modifiers that are rarely used. These are called the &lt;em&gt;Hyper key&lt;/em&gt; (shift+cmd+ctrl+option on Mac and shift+windows+ctrl+alt on Windows) and the &lt;em&gt;Meh key&lt;/em&gt; (shift+ctrl+option on Mac and shift+ctrl+alt on Windows). Both combinations are not the easiest to press; for example, for a keyboard shortcut that uses the Hyper key, you need to press four modifier keys and another key assigned to a shortcut. But many external keyboards have additional keys to which you can assign the Hyper or Meh keys (that&#39;s what I did with my Kinesis Advantage keyboard). Even the built-in keyboards have keys you can live without (the &amp;quot;Caps Lock&amp;quot; key is fairly unused - unless you need to &lt;em&gt;shout&lt;/em&gt; a lot on the internet) and can be converted into a special key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that before I buy the Stream Deck, I will first try to implement some useful macros. I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://folivora.ai/&quot;&gt;BetterTouchTool&lt;/a&gt; or BTT for short - my preferred way to define macros on a MacBook (I bought it years ago to customize the touchbar on my previous laptop, and I&#39;ve been using it ever since). I configured the &amp;quot;Esc&amp;quot; key to act as the Hyper (so &amp;quot;shift+cmd+ctrl+alt&amp;quot; ) and &amp;quot;Insert&amp;quot; to act as the Meh (so &amp;quot;shift+ctrl+alt&amp;quot;). Both those keys were previously unused - I&#39;m using &amp;quot;Caps Lock&amp;quot; as the Esc key and the &amp;quot;Insert&amp;quot; key is basically a second backslash key on the Kinesis Advantage2 keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;captioned-figure&quot;&gt;
    &lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/img/QUkww2jp73-250.webp 250w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/QUkww2jp73-600.webp 600w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/QUkww2jp73-751.webp 751w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 639px) calc(100vw - 32px), (max-width: 767px) 608px, (max-width: 960px) calc(100vw - 40px), 920px&quot; /&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/img/QUkww2jp73-250.jpeg 250w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/QUkww2jp73-600.jpeg 600w, https://lukemccrone.com/img/QUkww2jp73-751.jpeg 751w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 639px) calc(100vw - 32px), (max-width: 767px) 608px, (max-width: 960px) calc(100vw - 40px), 920px&quot; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Kinesis Advantage2 layout&quot; class=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/img/QUkww2jp73-250.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;751&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;An unused key on my keyboard that could be used as Meh&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I&#39;ve decided to make an easy-to-remember split of functionality of those custom shortcuts. The Hyper key would be used in shortcuts that start some applications, and the Meh key would be used for all the other macros. Ideally, the first letter of the application&#39;s name could be used as the shortcut to open it. So, for example, &lt;code&gt;Hyper + o&lt;/code&gt; would open the Obsidian app, &lt;code&gt;Hyper + i&lt;/code&gt; would start iTerm, and &lt;code&gt;Hyper + f&lt;/code&gt; would start Finder. Of course, not every app could have a shortcut like that (e.g. if two apps started with the same letter, one would need a different shortcut). But I&#39;ve decided to limit the number of application shortcuts to only those I use multiple times per day. If an app is already opened, pressing its shortcut will switch to the desktop with that app and bring it to the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, it was time for more advanced macros that I would use with the Meh modifier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Meh + m&lt;/code&gt;: mutes/unmutes the microphone. This shortcut triggers a &amp;quot;Run Apple Script (blocking)&amp;quot; from BTT that runs an &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/AliKarpuzoglu/a5ce01c5a3812094a91d3d6e22fd12b4&quot;&gt;applescript to toggle the current microphone&#39;s volume between 0 and 100&lt;/a&gt; and displays a notification. To make sure I don&#39;t get confused about whether my microphone is muted or not, I&#39;ve added &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.folivora.ai/t/microphone-mute-unmute-widget/1579&quot;&gt;this BTT widget&lt;/a&gt; to display an icon in the menu bar indicating the microphone&#39;s status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Meh + p&lt;/code&gt;: triggers the &amp;quot;Play/Pause&amp;quot; action in BTT to toggle the currently playing music or any other video or audio. I could achieve the same by pressing the button on my headphones, but still, my fingers are on the keyboard, so pressing a keyboard shortcut is faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Meh + n&lt;/code&gt;: sets the &amp;quot;Do not disturb&amp;quot; status for 1 hour. This hides all the notifications and is very useful during screen-sharing sessions, ensuring no weird message pops up in the middle of a presentation. I have an Apple Shortcut that sets the &amp;quot;Do not disturb&amp;quot; status and accepts a parameter defining how long it should be set. This shortcut comes with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://alfred.app/workflows/vitor/calm-notifications/&quot;&gt;Calm notifications&lt;/a&gt; workflow for Alfred, and all I have to do is trigger it from BTT with the &amp;quot;Run Shortcut from Shortcuts App&amp;quot; action (optionally followed by the &amp;quot;Show notification&amp;quot; action to get a popup confirming the correct execution of the shortcut).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Meh + t&lt;/code&gt;: brings the Teams window to the foreground. This is done by using the &amp;quot;Show/Hide Specific Application&amp;quot; action in BTT, and it saves me from figuring out where my Teams window is during calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the most useful shortcuts I could think of. This setup was not without flaws, and I solved them when I bought the Stream Deck. But it was good enough to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What were the flaws? For instance, the play/pause button usually works for the last piece of media content played, but sometimes it&#39;s a bit random. This was an issue when I had the Spotify app opened (which is always opened) and a YouTube video paused in one of the browser tabs. Sometimes, the macro would work on Spotify, when I wanted it to start the video, and sometimes it would start a video somewhere in my browser when I wanted it to stop the music &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/#fn3&quot; id=&quot;fnref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. That was quite annoying, and with Stream Deck, I&#39;ve solved this problem by having a separate button for Spotify and another one for other media content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try to get a mechanical keyboard, and you will quickly understand why muting is necessary. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was wrong with this statement. Pressing a button to open an app is sometimes more convenient. Especially when I&#39;m doing something else on my main screen and I can press the button on an external device without losing focus. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;And DJ &amp;quot;Spotify mixed with a random YouTube video&amp;quot; is terrible. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/you-dont-need-stream-deck-you-need-macros/#fnref3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <title>No &quot;Hello&quot;, No &quot;Quick Call&quot;, and no Meetings Without an Agenda</title>
      <link href="https://lukemccrone.com/blog/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/"/>
      <updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://lukemccrone.com/blog/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/</id>
      <summary>When working remotely, asking for help is often just a few keystrokes away. So it&#39;s tempting to &quot;quickly&quot; ask someone for support when you get stuck.</summary>
      <content type="html">
        <img alt="No &quot;Hello&quot;, No &quot;Quick Call&quot;, and no Meetings Without an Agenda" src="https://lukemccrone.com/posts/2024/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/cover.jpg"/>
        &lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably received a link to this website because you did one of the common mistakes of working remotely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You started a conversation by writing &amp;quot;Hi&amp;quot;, or  &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot;, or even maybe &amp;quot;Good morning Luke, I have a question&amp;quot;. And then you waited. And waited. And waited for minutes (or hours if I was busy and you were patient) without a single word explaining what problem you were facing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You asked me for a &amp;quot;quick call&amp;quot; (or maybe just a &amp;quot;call&amp;quot;) without explaining what you wanted to talk about in the hope that I would drop everything and jump right into helping you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You invited me to a meeting without a description or an agenda.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t worry, I&#39;m not mad at you. Those are common mistakes that people make when working remotely. Maybe you work in an environment where productivity is low, so everyone has time to jump on a quick call or chat with you any time you ask. Or maybe you&#39;re a manager, and no one has the courage to explain that all those interruptions are bad and show you how you can make them a bit &lt;em&gt;less bad&lt;/em&gt;. There is another possibility - you&#39;re lazy and selfish, so you don&#39;t care how your interruptions affect others because your questions need to be answered right now with minimal effort on your end. But I&#39;m sure that&#39;s not the case. We are all kind, hard-working people who care deeply about their team members, and we only sometimes need a little bit of additional guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain why those three remote-work mistakes are bad, how you can do things better, and why it&#39;s good &lt;strong&gt;for you&lt;/strong&gt; if you avoid them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-hello&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;No &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot; &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/#no-hello&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is so common that there is already a beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;https://nohello.net/en/&quot;&gt;nohello.net&lt;/a&gt; website explaining why it&#39;s better to ask your question directly instead of starting with &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot; and waiting for a reply before you ask the actual question. I&#39;m not going to repeat what the website says, but the gist is that if you write your question right away, you will get an answer much faster. There is really no need to wait for me to come and &amp;quot;Hi&amp;quot; back before you start writing what&#39;s the problem. Especially since I might get busy again and the wait time will get longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is more than that to the &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot; problem, especially if you want to ask for technical assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me show you different ways of asking about the same thing, sorted from the &lt;em&gt;worst&lt;/em&gt; way to ask a question to the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; one. Let&#39;s say I added a new argument to a function called &lt;code&gt;frobnicate&lt;/code&gt; but forgot to update the usage of this function in all the places in the code. And now you are facing a problem caused by that, and decide to ask for help:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Hi&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot;, or even &amp;quot;Hi, I have a question&amp;quot;. This is absolutely the worst way to start a conversation when you have a problem. I have no clue what you want or if it&#39;s urgent. And you&#39;re waiting until I&#39;m around my keyboard to answer &amp;quot;Hi&amp;quot; before you get a chance to explain your issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, the &lt;code&gt;frobnicate&lt;/code&gt; function doesn&#39;t work&amp;quot;. Ok, at least we have a bit of context about the topic of our conversation. But I still have no clue what you mean by &amp;quot;doesn&#39;t work&amp;quot;. Is the function throwing an error, or does it not work as expected? Is it happening on your computer, or did it stop working in production, and the company is losing millions every minute?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, I tried running the &lt;code&gt;frobnicate&lt;/code&gt; function in the staging environment, but it&#39;s throwing &lt;code&gt;Error: missing argument &#39;count&#39;&lt;/code&gt;. I&#39;m on the &#39;feature-123&#39; code branch&amp;quot;. Sweet, we&#39;re almost there. I know what function you&#39;re calling, in what context, and what error you get. But we can still do better.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is another very misleading version of this question that can set us both on a path of debugging a wrong problem. Compare the previous version with the following one: &amp;quot;Hi, I tried running the &lt;code&gt;frobnicate&lt;/code&gt; function in the staging environment, but it&#39;s throwing an error about the count argument. I&#39;m on the &#39;feature-123&#39; code branch&amp;quot;. And now imagine that you simply misspelled the word &amp;quot;count&amp;quot; in your function, which I would immediately spot if I saw the full error. But I didn&#39;t see the whole error and instead wrongly assumed that the issue was with the &lt;code&gt;frobnicate&lt;/code&gt; function itself. So we both embark on a completely needless adventure of changing random parts of the code and scratching our heads as to why nothing makes the error go away. I end up wasting hours because of a typo. That&#39;s why I strongly recommend including the stack trace in your message (and not only the last error but the full stack track because often the crucial part is somewhere in the middle). Or at least pasting the exact error message instead of trying to describe with your words what &lt;em&gt;you think&lt;/em&gt; is not working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, I tried running the &lt;code&gt;frobnicate&lt;/code&gt; function in the staging environment, but it&#39;s throwing &lt;code&gt;Error: missing argument &#39;count&#39;&lt;/code&gt;. I&#39;m on the &#39;feature-123&#39; code branch. I compared this with the production environment, and there it works. I also pulled the latest changes from Steve. Here is the full stack trace: (...)&amp;quot;. This is the perfect example of asking for help online. It not only gives the exact error message and the context in which it happens but also explains what you have tried so far, so I can avoid giving you advice like &amp;quot;Compare it with the production environment&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Did you pull the latest code?&amp;quot; because I know you already tried that. Honestly, this is such a good and concrete ask that I will probably make the additional effort to at least think about the possible solution, even if I&#39;m in the middle of doing something else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-quick-call&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;No &amp;quot;quick call&amp;quot; &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/#no-quick-call&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very similar problem to the &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot; one, except that you now want to move from the &lt;em&gt;asynchronous&lt;/em&gt; way of solving the problem to the &lt;em&gt;synchronous&lt;/em&gt; one. And just like with &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot;, asking for a &amp;quot;quick call&amp;quot; has a couple of problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A call is more distracting than a chat message. I can answer a simple message or two in a chat without losing the context of what I&#39;m currently working on. But for calls, I need to focus more attention, and thus, it takes much longer to recover. You may think you took 30 seconds of my time, but it&#39;s always more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes, a message is enough. Some calls are basically equivalent to exchanging a few messages on the chat. Congratulations, you just saved yourself 10 seconds of writing down your question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking (or rather, &lt;em&gt;writing&lt;/em&gt;) yourself through the problem can help you solve it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rubber_duck_debugging&quot;&gt;The rubber duck debugging&lt;/a&gt; really works. I&#39;ve witnessed countless times when, after explaining the issue, the message was deleted or followed by &amp;quot;never mind&amp;quot; because my interlocutor figured out how to fix the problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Calls are ephemeral. Written messages are eternal&lt;/em&gt;. At least until the servers go down or the company hosting your favorite chat app goes bust. But the best thing about written words is that you can always come back later and find this conversation, reminding yourself how to solve a specific problem or why you decided to fix it in a specific way&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I answer your &amp;quot;Quick call?&amp;quot; with &amp;quot;What&#39;s the problem?&amp;quot;, that&#39;s really for your own good 😉. I want you to think through the problem and have an answer written down for the future without completely distracting me from my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of what I wrote about the &amp;quot;quick call&amp;quot; can also apply to the &lt;em&gt;last horseman of wasted time in a remote environment&lt;/em&gt; that&#39;s coming up next. However, this metaphor doesn&#39;t make that much sense if there are only three of them. Want to help me find the 4th horseman? Leave a comment about what other ways of wasting peoples&#39; time deserve that title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-agenda-meetings&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;No agenda&amp;quot; meetings &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/#no-agenda-meetings&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been invited to a meeting and had no clue what it was going to be about until you actually joined it? Ahh, yes, the &amp;quot;no agenda&amp;quot; meetings, or as I like to call them - the &amp;quot;surprise meetings&amp;quot;. Apparently, for some people, wasting the time of one other person is not enough, so they invite multiple people &amp;quot;just in case they are needed&amp;quot;. And who needs an agenda when all the talking points are safely stored in your head?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to apply the &amp;quot;no agenda, no attenda&amp;quot; rule (which means I try to decline meetings with no agenda). While it works for me, I don&#39;t think others may be in such a comfortable situation and have such understanding managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having an agenda or at least a detailed description has so many benefits that literally nothing justifies &amp;quot;agenda-less&amp;quot; meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I know the agenda upfront, I can prepare for the meeting. If I need to check something or refresh my memory, I can do this in advance without wasting everyone&#39;s time. If we need to make a decision, I can think about possible options and prepare a list of pros and cons if the decision is tough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I can answer all the questions from the agenda with a message - congratulations, we just saved everyone&#39;s time by not having a meeting!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An agenda gives the meeting a purpose and a checklist. Are we there to make a decision? Great, we can wrap up the meeting as soon as we make one. Are we there to understand some topics? Great, let&#39;s prepare a checklist to make sure we stay on track and not forget anything. With an agenda, it&#39;s easier to see if we have already discussed everything that was needed or if we have fulfilled the purpose of the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can see if I&#39;m even needed in that meeting. Sometimes, I get invited to a meeting only because I&#39;m leading a project or a team, but the meeting is completely non-technical and requires no input from me. Occasionally, I&#39;m even invited to a meeting that&#39;s not even about my project. If I knew upfront what the meeting would be about, I could skip it or plan my time accordingly. For example, if I know that the meeting will most likely not require much input from my side, but I should still participate in case a technical question is raised, I will simply plan to do some code reviews with the meeting running in the background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you invite a technical person like me to a meeting, you most likely want one of three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want me to explain something completely new to you. If I know upfront what that is, I can send you a link to the relevant documentation. Then, usually, one of two things happens.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You find all your answers in the documentation, so the meeting is no longer needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You read/skim the documentation and have at least a basic understanding of what we will talk about, so the eventual meeting will be much more productive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to ask a specific technical question. It&#39;s better to ask it in writing because I can think about my answer and do the necessary research at my own pace. I won&#39;t be wasting your (and possibly other people&#39;s) time during the meeting searching for the answer or giving you a wrong one because you rushed me and I didn&#39;t have time to consider all the factors carefully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to ask me about something I did in the past. As in the previous point, I need some time to refresh my memory and prepare. Look, technology is a very fast-moving environment. That feature I built two months ago? In the meantime, I probably built three other things, and I completely forgot how the thing you want to ask me about works. Spending 10 minutes alone preparing for the meeting is an effective approach. It&#39;s better than spending 30 minutes &lt;strong&gt;during&lt;/strong&gt; the meeting franticly jumping through the code, trying to remember what each function did, and either answering your questions in the meantime or feeling the weight of silence when you look at my screen and all the mistakes I make when typing. Not to mention that we would be wasting 30 minutes of time for multiple people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;content-context-is-king&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;s&gt;Content&lt;/s&gt; Context is king &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/#content-context-is-king&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working remotely, asking for help is often just a few keystrokes away. So it&#39;s tempting to &amp;quot;quickly&amp;quot; ask someone for help when you get stuck. But unlike when you&#39;re in an office, you can&#39;t easily see if that other person is busy and whether or not you will interrupt them (unless they remember to set the &amp;quot;don&#39;t disturb&amp;quot; status in the messaging app).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But to get the best help, you must also make some effort:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe the problem you&#39;re facing with as many details as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to explain your problem in a written form before you jump on a call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When planning a meeting, let everyone prepare by outlining a clear agenda for the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust me, this will make all your online interactions more efficient, and you will solve your problems much faster. It will also make your peers &lt;em&gt;want to help&lt;/em&gt; you instead of taking a deep breath and closing the chat window each time they get a &amp;quot;Hi&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Quick call?&amp;quot; message from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot; /&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, if your chat application has a working &amp;quot;search&amp;quot; feature. Yes, I&#39;m looking at you Microsoft Teams, and your atrocious search functionality that, for years, could not find a simple message in my chats. &lt;a href=&quot;https://lukemccrone.com/blog/no-hello-no-quick-call-no-agendaless-meetings/#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
</feed>
